

CONTACT ME

✓ osk.bjorns90@gmail.com

40 43 90 87

• København

LINKS

LinkedIn:

Ósk Björns

GitHub:

OskinB

SKILLS

React

Next.js

Vue

JavaScript

TypeScript

TailwindCSS

CSS // SASS

Figma

UX // UI Design

REST API

GitHub

Firebase

GraphQL

Cypress

LANGUAGES

Icelandic (native)

English (fluent)

HOBBIES

In my free time, I like to keep my mind active by reading, playing video games, solving puzzles, listening to diverse music, and enjoying screen-free time outdoors.

ÓSK BJÖRNSDÓTTIR

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

I'm passionate about problem-solving, crafting pixel-perfect, responsive user interfaces and UX design. My attention to detail, organizational skills, and drive to work with creative teams fuel my enthusiasm for all things frontend.

My experiences have prepared me to understand project development from start to finish, the importance of good planning, teamwork collaboration and communication.

Volunteer:

BSides Copenhagen 2021 - DefensiveCTF challenge creator (frontend).

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

Numerous (Start-up from Energy Machines) // May 2022 - Dec 2024

Designed and implemented frontend features for the Numerous platform.

Lead developer and designer for the Numerous website.

React, Next.js, TypeScript, TailwindCSS, Firebase, GraphQL, Cypress.

Consulting & Web Development

Self-employed // 2020 - 2021

Built and designed websites with tailored solutions for the client's needs.

Sales

Ikea // Summer 2019

Sales agent for the living room department.

Airport Security

Isavia // 2011 - 2018

Airport security officer at FLE International Airport.

Dance Instructor & Project Manager

DansKompaní // 2010 - 2017

Dance instructor and coordinator.

EDUCATION

B.A. // Web Development

KEA Københavns Erhvervsakademi // 2020 - 2022

Developing skills to a professional level by managing the entire process of designing and building applications for the web in projects of all sizes.

Diploma, Graduated With Honors // Web Development

Reykjavík Academy of Web Development // 2018 - 2020

Program with a focus on frontend and product development. Included backend development to create a complete application.

Diploma // Programming

The New Computer and Business School // 2017 - 2018

A comprehensive program that teaches key competencies that developers need to work in software development.

High School Diploma // Contemporary Dance

Danslistarskóli JSB // 2007 - 2010

High School Diploma // Languages

Fjölbrautaskóli Suðurnesja // 2006 - 2010

INTERNSHIP

Frontend Developer

Dwarf // August - October 2021 (KEA)

Worked on projects using Vue/Nuxt, TailwindCSS, and Prismic CMS.

Frontend Developer

Reon // January - May 2020 (Reykjavík Academy of Web Development)
Lead programmer for the final React exam project, in which we
collaborated with Reon, a software development company.